<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache ShenYu on ShenYu</title><link>/categories/apache-shenyu/</link><description>Recent content in Apache ShenYu on ShenYu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/apache-shenyu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>【Apache ShenYu gateway version2.2.0 release】Make high-performance gateways so easy!</title><link>/community/shenyu-2.2.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/shenyu-2.2.0/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the new features first, and then I would like to share my story. Completely pluggable architecture design, plug-in hot swap. Fully supports all versions of Dubbo, Alibaba-Dubbo, Apache-Dubbo. Support Dubbo generalization call, multi-parameter, complex parameter interface. Enhance the monitor plug-in and remove the Influxdb, add metrics such as memory, CPU, QPS, TPS, response delay, and support access to Prometheus. The SpringCloud plugin supports Eureka and</description></item><item><title>How convenient is the 2.1.X version of Apache ShenYu Gateway?</title><link>/community/shenyu-2.1.x/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/shenyu-2.1.x/</guid><description>It has been a year since I open sourced ShenYu gateway in October last year, and received many suggestions from you guys in community. It has provided very rich functions after optimization, many of functions are highly cusmized, visualized, and highly extensible, now let&amp;rsquo;s make a summary. Plugin Provides various plug-ins, such as signature, monitoring, rate limiting, circuit breaker, Http proxy, Dubbo proxy, Websocket, etc. Support users to quickly develop</description></item><item><title>Apache ShenYu Code Conduct</title><link>/community/code-conduct/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/code-conduct/</guid><description>Development Guidelines Write codes with heart. Pursue clean, simplified and extremely elegant codes. Agree with concepts in &amp;lt;Refactoring: Improving the Design of Existing Code&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship&amp;gt;. Be familiar with codes already had, to keep consistent with the style and use. Highly reusable, no duplicated codes or configurations. Delete codes out of use in time. Contributor Covenant Submitting of Conduct Make sure all the test cases are passed, Make sure .</description></item><item><title>Apache ShenYu Committer</title><link>/community/committer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/committer/</guid><description>Committer Promotion After you have made a lot of contributions, the community will nominate. Become a committer you will have
Permissions written by ShenYu repository Idea is used legally Committer Responsibilities Develop new features; Refactor codes; Review pull requests reliably and in time; Consider and accept feature requests; Answer questions; Update documentation and example; Improve processes and tools; Guide new contributors join community. Committer Routine A committer needs to review every day the Pull Request and issue list to be processed by the community, and assign a suitable committer, that is, Assignee.</description></item><item><title>Apache ShenYu Contributor</title><link>/community/contributor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/contributor/</guid><description>You can report a bug, submit a new function enhancement suggestion, or submit a pull request directly.
Submit an Issue Before submitting an issue, please go through a comprehensive search to make sure the problem cannot be solved just by searching. Check the Issue List to make sure the problem is not repeated. Create a new issue and choose the type of issue. Define the issue with a clear and descriptive title.</description></item><item><title>Apache ShenYu Gateway released version 1.0.4-RELEASE</title><link>/community/shenyu-1.0.4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/shenyu-1.0.4/</guid><description>ShenYu Gateway released version 1.0.4-RELEASE Fix the bug that appeared in the Soul-admin of version 1.0.3. The serialization method supports custom extensions. The default serialization method has been changed from Kroy to Java serialization method. Dubbo support. Changes Dubbo usage In the previous version (1.0.2 or 1.0.3), the parameters of Dubbo are passed through the header, and in the 1.0.4 version it is passed through the body.</description></item></channel></rss>