<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache ShenYu on ShenYu</title><link>/tags/apache-shenyu/</link><description>Recent content in Apache ShenYu on ShenYu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/apache-shenyu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>【Apache ShenYu gateway version2.2.0 release】Make high-performance gateways so easy!</title><link>/news/shenyu-2.2.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/shenyu-2.2.0/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the new features first, and then I would like to share my story. Completely pluggable architecture design, plug-in hot swap. Fully supports all versions of Dubbo, Alibaba-Dubbo, Apache-Dubbo. Support Dubbo generalization call, multi-parameter, complex parameter interface. Enhance the monitor plug-in and remove the Influxdb, add metrics such as memory, CPU, QPS, TPS, response delay, and support access to Prometheus. The SpringCloud plugin supports Eureka and</description></item><item><title>How convenient is the 2.1.X version of Apache ShenYu Gateway?</title><link>/news/shenyu-2.1.x/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/shenyu-2.1.x/</guid><description>It has been a year since I open sourced ShenYu gateway in October last year, and received many suggestions from you guys in community. It has provided very rich functions after optimization, many of functions are highly cusmized, visualized, and highly extensible, now let&amp;rsquo;s make a summary. Plugin Provides various plug-ins, such as signature, monitoring, rate limiting, circuit breaker, Http proxy, Dubbo proxy, Websocket, etc. Support users to quickly develop</description></item><item><title>Apache ShenYu Gateway released version 1.0.4-RELEASE</title><link>/news/shenyu-1.0.4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/shenyu-1.0.4/</guid><description>ShenYu Gateway released version 1.0.4-RELEASE Fix the bug that appeared in the Soul-admin of version 1.0.3. The serialization method supports custom extensions. The default serialization method has been changed from Kroy to Java serialization method. Dubbo support. Changes Dubbo usage In the previous version (1.0.2 or 1.0.3), the parameters of Dubbo are passed through the header, and in the 1.0.4 version it is passed through the body.</description></item></channel></rss>